Kearney Taaffe

817-239-2783 | <u>kearney.taaffe@gmail.com</u> | 3260 Pablo Cir, RR, TX 78665

github.com/gitKearney | linkedin.com/in/kearney-taaffe-518a2218

PROFILE

Full Stack Engineer with 7 years specializing in building web applications using React and VueJS. Over 9 years of architecting and developing APIs in PHP and ExpressJS. Over 9 years configuring servers to host APIs. I'm passionate about creating functional code that is easy to update, extend, and test.

SKILLS

- LANGUAGES: PHP | NodeJS | bash | TypeScript | JavaScript
- DATABASE: MariaDB, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, PostgreSQL JSONB
- **JAVASCRIPT:** React, Redux Toolkit, Zustand, Wouter, Vue3, Pinia, Material UI, Vite, Vitest, Jest, Mocha, Enzyme, MobX
- **DevOps:** FireBase, AWS Route 53, AWS S3, EC2, NginX, Lighttpd, MariaDB replication
- **3rd Party:** Okta, Stripe (Express), PayPal (PHP), JWT, NodeMailer, PUG Templates

EXPERIENCE

Softrams / Full Stack Engineer

Nov 2022 - Present

Technologies: React, Vue, Stripe, Express, Primsa, PostgreSQL JSONB

- Greenfielded a VueJS front-end using Material UI
- Worked extensively creating an API using Express, Prisma, and PostgreSQL
- Integrated Stripe API into Express API
- Rewrote VueJS FE into React using MUI

Meeting Protocol Worldwide / Senior Front-End Engineer

Sept 2021 - Oct 2022

Technologies: PHP Symfony, MongoDB, Docker, Bootstrap5

- Upgrade PHP web application from Symfony 2 to Symfony 5
- Tweaked MongoDB schemas to be more performant
- Developed and deployed a new front-end in BootStrap 5

Visa / Software Engineer | Contractor

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

Technologies: React, Redux Sagas

- Developed a library of styled components to create a component library that allowed for "drop in" development into templates
- Fixed components to be ADA compliant by fixing focus issues and allowing keyboard or mouse usage
- Wrote extensive code coverage tests using Chai and React Testing Library

Rodeo Logistics / Full Stack Engineer | Contractor

Apr 2020 - Jan 2021

Technologies: React, Node, MS SQL server

- Developed a web application to extract, transform, and load scores from a file to a MS SOL API
- Worked on a team to migrate from React class components to function components using useState and useEffect
- Performed code reviews and helped write unit testing in Mocha for both the Node API and the React front-end

Leading Reach / Full Stack Developer

Aug 2019 - Feb 2020

Technologies: Symfony, Angular 1.4, MySQL

- Successfully maintained a Symfony API by fixing bugs and creating new MySQL stored procedures for customer reports
- Enhanced an Angular web application by fixing bugs, adding new features
- Deployed new releases using Travis for CI
- Performed code reviews; Participated in backlog grooming and breaking epics down

MacMillan Learning / Full Stack Developer | Contractor

Mar 2018 - Aug 2019

Technologies: React, Redux, a11y, Jest, Mocha, Chai, Docker

- Worked with a small team to develop a cutting edge online learning tool, that allowed for automated grading of homework & tests
- Fixed issues with a MySQL Node API and successfully deployed fixes using Docker and Jenkins
- Utilized BDD & TDD to build highly complex web applications that were a11y compliant

LegacyBeta / Laravel Developer | Contractor

Oct 2017 - Feb 2018

Technologies: Laravel, React, QuickBooks API, MariaDB, NginX/Lighttpd

- Worked with client to migrate a Laravel web application to React and Lumen
- Integrated with the QuickBooks API to generate reports on sales, billing, and to generate invoices
- Maintained Linux server with nginx and PHP-FPM and tuned MySQL DB

Finance Genius / Full Stack Developer | Contractor

Jan 2017 - Oct 2017

- Integrated the NADA API into a Codeigniter web app
- Developed a KnockoutJS web app that modified PDF files
- Figured out how to setup all development environments using Docker and xDebug

Pecan Street Project / RaspberryPi Developer | Contractor

Feb 2016 - Jan 2017

Technologies: Python3, CherryPy, PHP, Angular 1.3, Vis.JS

- Built an API using CherryPy on a RaspberryPi to control sprinkler systems
- Extended an Angular SPA to display power generation graphs using Vis.JS
- Built a web-scraper using Python and BeautifulSoup to download, unzip, and parse CSV and XLS files from ERCOT

Perk / API Developer

Nov 2015 - Feb 2016

Technologies: Laravel, PHP 5.6, API

 Worked with Android game developers to develop an API to keep track of player time, win-loss ratio, and in-game currency

Krush Communication / IVR Engineer

May 2014 - Oct 2015

Technologies: MS SQL, DigiTalk, IVR Engineer, Zend 1, PHP, JS

- Developed IVR systems using DigiTalk and MS SQL stored procedures
- Fixed issues with Zend 1 framework
- Performed routine maintenance and upgrades of PHP web-app and IVR app

Emmis Communication / Web Developer II

Aug 2013 - April 2014

Technologies: PHP, Kohana, VisJS, Wordpress, CSS

- Extended and maintained an in-house ticketing system written in Kohana 3.5
- Created new reports using Vis.JS to display metrics of user engagement
- Performed routine maintenance and upgrades of a WordPress site

Affinegy / Software Engineer

Aug 2009 - June 2013

Technology: Java, PHP, CSS, AWS

- Created custom branded websites to host software downloads for clients
- Created a TR-69 compliant web server to communicate with routers
- Created TR-69 scripts to issue updates to routers
- Used RightScale to maintain AWS server

NetworkIP - Jaduka / Telephony Engineer

Jan 2006 - June 2009

Technology: Python, Java, PHP, MySQL, InformixDB

- Developed IVR applications that allowed for processing credit card payments
- Developed an API to communicate with PayPal and CyberSource
- Configured Lighttpd servers to run PHP code
- Worked on a team to convert 1.7M lines of Java code to Python & PHP
- Worked on a team to convert a C application to Python

Education

University of Texas Arlington / Computer Science & Electrical Engineering